<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Simulation on sixman.guru</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/simulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Simulation on sixman.guru</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.155.3</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 12:54:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/simulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>East and Throckmorton likely to rule UIL D2 Six-Man Playoffs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/east-and-throckmorton-likely-to-rule-uil-d2-six-man-playoffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 12:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/east-and-throckmorton-likely-to-rule-uil-d2-six-man-playoffs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After 100,000 simulations, the Throckmorton Greyhounds appear to have a 29.8% chance to win the UIL D2 Six-Man State Championship. The biggest challenge it appears will be the dominance of the East bracket, which won a dominating 80.1% of the time in the simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I wrote about how the Crowell Wildcats are a somewhat dominant 33.1% to repeat as the D1 UIL State Six-Man Champions. If you would like to read more details on the methods, I have several posted below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oakland, Pittsburgh slight favorites in Wild Card probabilities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/oakland-pittsburgh-slight-favorites-in-wild-card-probabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 09:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/oakland-pittsburgh-slight-favorites-in-wild-card-probabilities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- AdSense Now! V3.40 --&gt;
&lt;!-- Post[count: 1] --&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;adsense adsense-leadin&#34; style=&#34;float:right;margin: 12px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- Guru2013 --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the MLB Playoffs beginning this evening, I figured it was time to test my rankings and pull out the old &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sixmanguru.com/generic-sports-series-probability-calculator/&#34;&gt;probability calculator&lt;/a&gt;. I created the MLB Ratings based on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sixmanguru.com/nfl-week-14-predictions-ratings-optimization-and-non-linear-programming/&#34;&gt;simple least squares NLP Optimization&lt;/a&gt; that I have discussed before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Oakland at Kansas City&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Royals are in the playoffs for the first time in ages and they get to host a game. Unfortunately, they didn’t seem to have a home field advantage during the regular season, so I am not sure how much this helps (although in reality we can assume it does, at least a little). The numbers say the A’s are the better team by almost 0.7 of a run (per game, for the season). I show them as a 63.5% favorite.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NCAA Men’s DI Tennis Regionals Simulated 50,000 times</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ncaa-mens-di-tennis-regionals-simulated-50000-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 12:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ncaa-mens-di-tennis-regionals-simulated-50000-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- AdSense Now! V3.40 --&gt;
&lt;!-- Post[count: 1] --&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;adsense adsense-leadin&#34; style=&#34;float:right;margin: 12px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- Guru2013 --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is posted on my college tennis website so aptly named, &lt;a href=&#34;http://texascollegetennis.com/&#34;&gt;texascollegetennis.com&lt;/a&gt;. I decided to post it here as well.. why not, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sitting in the middle of exams and term projects looking for ways to relax. What better way than to run a Monte Carlo Simulation of each of the men’s regionals, based on my year-end ratings?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
