<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>SQL on sixman.guru</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SQL on sixman.guru</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.155.3</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 16:46:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating Maps on the Fly For UIL Realignment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-maps-on-the-fly-for-uil-realignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 16:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-maps-on-the-fly-for-uil-realignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This morning the high school football season officially started with the release of the much anticipated 2014-2016 UIL Football Alignments. This usually started with the UIL servers crashing due to the high volume of traffic (it did briefly, prior to release). This year the UIL was prepared and had a back-up plan to divert traffic off their site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So at exactly 9:00 am, the Twitterverse was alive with the ramblings of everyone who cares about Texas high school football.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converting College Football Data for a Simple Website, using PHP, SQL and MySQL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/converting-college-football-data-for-a-simple-website-using-php-sql-and-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 22:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/converting-college-football-data-for-a-simple-website-using-php-sql-and-mysql/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The pages discussed here can be found at: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sixmanguru.com/ncaa13.php&#34;&gt;http://www.sixmanguru.com/ncaa13.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of this project came from a thought that there does not exist a single place where you can see NCAA college football teams’ records and schedules easily, without having to make a bunch of clicks on very ‘graphically full’ websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step was to see if the data could be found easily. This was done easily, as Peter Wolfe keeps this information updated daily. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://prwolfe.bol.ucla.edu/cfootball/scores.htm&#34;&gt;http://prwolfe.bol.ucla.edu/cfootball/scores.htm&lt;/a&gt;). Wolfe is a member of the official BCS rankings and also includes a comprehensive listing of conferences as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
