<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Grand Slam on sixman.guru</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/grand-slam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grand Slam on sixman.guru</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.155.3</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 00:36:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/grand-slam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Federer-Tursunov and other Friday French Open Matches Using Markov Chain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/predicting-federer-friday-french-open-matches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 00:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/predicting-federer-friday-french-open-matches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- AdSense Now! V3.40 --&gt;
&lt;!-- Post[count: 1] --&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;adsense adsense-leadin&#34; style=&#34;float:right;margin: 12px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- Guru2013 --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I was enamored with the FiveThirtyEight.com article, &lt;a href=&#34;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/inside-the-shadowy-world-of-high-speed-tennis-betting/&#34; title=&#34;538.com&#34;&gt;Inside the Shadowy World of High-Speed Tennis Betting&lt;/a&gt;. The article mentions the courtsiders who would sit court side at a tennis match and try to relay information quicker than the tournament computers to betting partners. Great read. Not sure these courtsiders were really doing anything illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buried deep in the article was a mention of the system this one organization created to predict the outcome of tennis matches for betting purposes. It links to a website, Summer of Jeff, and a post, &lt;a href=&#34;http://summerofjeff.wordpress.com/2011/01/13/python-code-for-tennis-markov/&#34; title=&#34;Summer of Jeff&#34;&gt;Python Code for Tennis Markov&lt;/a&gt;. If you follow the links to the gitHub site, there is some pretty elaborate Python code for generating probabilities based on &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markov_chain&#34; title=&#34;Markov&#34;&gt;Markov Chain theory&lt;/a&gt;. The code is pretty easy to use, if you understand Python and statistics, although it needs some cleaning up if you plan on using it for entire match prediction (hint: the matchProbs function needs some fixes to run).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
